PRITAM SARKAR

linkedin.com/in/sarkarpritam/ Kingston, ON, Canada pritam.sarkar@queensu.ca www.pritamsarkar.com

SUMMARY

Currently, I am a Ph.D. student at Queen's University and Postgraduate Affiliate at Vector Institute. My primary research interests include self/un-supervised learning, computer vision, video understanding, and multi-modal (vision+x) representation learning. Additionally, I am interested in areas of continual learning, responsible AI, generative models, and time-series representation learning among a few others.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy May 2020 - present

Kingston, Canada

Kingston, Canada

Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Queen's University

Advisor: Prof. Ali Etemad

GPA: 4.3/4.3

Master Applied Science Sept 2018 - Apr 2020

Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Queen's University

Thesis title: Self-Supervised ECG Representation Learning for Affective Computing.

Advisor: Prof. Ali Etemad

GPA: 3.8/4.3

Bachelor of Technology Aug 2011 - Jul 2015 Kolkata, India

Dept. of Electrical Engineering, West Bengal University of Technology

Rank 4 of 150 in graduating class of the Department of Electrical Engineering.

GPA: 8.84/10

PUBLICATIONS

As per google scholar, my publications have total citations of approx. 210 with h-index 6.

Conferences

- 8. P. Sarkar, A. Etemad, "XKD: Cross-modal Knowledge Distillation with Domain Alignment for Video Representation Learning", Under Review at CVPR 2023.
- 7. P. Sarkar, A. Posen, A. Etemad, "AVCAffe: A Large Scale Audio-Visual Dataset of Cognitive Load and Affect for Remote Work", arxiv:2205.06887, 2022, AAAI, 2023.
- 6. P. Sarkar, A. Etemad, "Self-supervised Audio-Visual Representation Learning with Relaxed Cross-Modal Synchronicity", arxiv:2111.05329, 2021, AAAI, 2023.
- 5. P. Sarkar, A. Etemad, "CardioGAN: Attentive Generative Adversarial Network with Dual Discriminators for Synthesis of ECG from PPG", AAAI, 2021.
- 4. R. Phinnemore, G. Cimolino, P. Sarkar, A. Etemad, T.C. N. Graham, "Happy Driver: Investigating the Effect of Mood on Preferred Style of Driving in Self-Driving Cars". HAI, 2021.
- 3. P. Sarkar, A. Etemad, "Self-supervised Learning for ECG-based Emotion Recognition", ICASSP, 2020.
- 2. P. Sarkar, K. Ross, A. Ruberto, D. Rodenburg, P. Hungler, A. Etemad, "Classification of Cognitive Load and Expertise for Adaptive Simulation using Deep Multitask Learning", ACII, 2019.
- 1. P. Sarkar, V. Davoodnia, A. Etemad, "Computer-Aided Diagnosis using Class-Weighted Deep Neural Networks", ICMLA, 2019.

Journals

- 4. P. Sarkar*, S. Lobmaier*, B. Fabre, G. Berg, A. Mueller, M. G. Frasch, M. C. Antonelli, A. Etemad, "Detection of Maternal and Fetal Stress from ECG with Self-supervised Representation Learning", Scientific Reports, 2021.
- 3. P. Sarkar, A. Etemad, "Self-supervised ECG Representation Learning for Emotion Recognition", IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing, 2020.
- 2. A. Ruberto, D. Rodenburg, K. Ross, P. Sarkar, P. Hungler, A. Etemad, D. Howes, D. Clarke, J. McLellan, D. Wilson, A. Szulewski, "The future of simulation based medical education: Adaptive simulation utilizing a deep multitask neural network", AEM Education and Training, 2021.
- 1. K. Ross, P. Sarkar, D. Rodenburg, A. Ruberto, P. Hungler, D. Howes, A. Szulewski, A. Etemad, "Toward Dynamically Adaptive Simulation: Multimodal Classification of User Expertise using Wearable Devices", Sensors, 2019.

Patents

1. P. Sarkar, A. Etemad, "Title withheld", US Patent Application, 63/085,394, 2020.

EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Research Intern at Borealis AI, Canada

Postgraduate Affiliate at Vector Institute, Canada

Sept 2022 - Present Mar 2021 - Present

Research Assistant at Queen's University, Canada

Aug 2018 - Present

I am a Research Assistant at *Ingenuity Lab* and *AIIM Lab* at Queen's University. My research is primarily focused on self-supervised learning, to learn meaningful representations without (or with minimal) human supervision. Please see my website to find out more about my research.

Lecturer/Teaching Assistant at Queen's University, Canada

Aug 2018 - Present

- Guest Lecturer for ELEC 872 (Artificial Intelligence and Interactive Systems), Fall 2022.
- Head Teaching Assistant for ELEC 472 (Artificial Intelligence) in winter 2022.
- Teaching Assistant for ELEC 472 (Artificial Intelligence) in winter 2021.
- Course Developer for ELEC 252 (Electronics I) in Fall 2020.
- Teaching Assistant for APSC 143 (Introduction to Computer Programming for Engineers) in Fall 2019.
- Course Developer for ELEC 472 (Artificial Intelligence and Interactive Systems) in summer 2019.

Sr. System Engineer at Infosys Ltd., India

Dec 2017 - Jul 2018

Software Engineer at Tech Mahindra Ltd., India

Nov 2015 - Nov 2017

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Mentorship

- Aaron Posen, ECE at Queen's University, undergrad final year project, 2021.
- Rachel Phinnemore, CS at Queen's University, undergrad final year project, 2020.

Reviewing/PC Member

- IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing (T-AFFC), 2022 Present.
- IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence (T-AI), 2021 Present.
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.
- IEEE Affective Computing and Intelligent Interaction (ACII), 2021, 2022.
- IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2020.
- IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC), 2019, 2020.
- ACM Symposium on Applied Perception (SAP), 2019.
- ECCV Workshop on Visual Object-oriented Learning meets Interaction (VOLI), 2022.

Organizing workshops and conferences

- Workflow and Publicity Chair AAAI 2023 Workshop on Representation Learning for Responsible Human-centric AI (R2HCAI).
- Workflow chair at AAAI 2022 Workshop on Human Centric Self-supervised Learning (HCSSL).
- Served in the organizing committee of AI/GI/CRV Conference, 2019.

Memberships/Others

- Student Rep. in Graduate Studies Academic Advisory (GSAC) Committee, Dept. of ECE, Queen's University, 2020 2021.
- PhD Rep. at Graduate Electrical and Computer Engineering (GECE) student council, Queen's University, 2020 2021.

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS/AWARDS

- Best Poster Honourable Mention at FEAS Research Symposium at Queen's University, 2022.
- Best Poster Honourable Mention at Robotics and Al Symposium at Ingenuity Labs, 2022.
- Best Poster Award at Robotics and AI Symposium at Ingenuity Labs, 2021.
- Postgraduate Affiliate Award, Vector Institute, 2021 Present.
- Graduate Research Fellowship, Queen's University, 2020 Present.
- Graduate Research Scholarship, Queen's University, 2019 2020.

SKILLS

Deep Learning: PyTorch*, TensorFlow

Programming Languages: Python*, MATLAB, C, SQL, PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, UNIX

* indicates primary preference

CREATIVE INTERESTS

· Short-Film Making and Photography